<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Lilley</title>
    <link>https://MikeLilley.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Lilley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://MikeLilley.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Primer on Tensors</title>
      <link>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/structure-tensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/structure-tensor/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we&amp;#39;ll be taking a brief look at tensors. These can be confusing objects to understand, but are central to many areas in mathematics, physics, and computer science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicial Homology</title>
      <link>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/simplicial_homology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/simplicial_homology/</guid>
      <description>We discuss the problem of hole-counting within topological spaces. Following an example motivated by graphs, we find that certain topological spaces can be triangulated to objects called simplicial complexes. We then develop a framework to compute holes by counting the independent cycles in a simplicial complex. Finally, we formalize this framework into the concept of homology groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideal Membership and Constraint Satisfaction Problems</title>
      <link>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/ideal-csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/ideal-csp/</guid>
      <description>We will be describing the application of the ideal membership problem (IMP) and Gröbner bases to the problem of deciding constraint satisfaction problems (CSPs). We will begin with an exposition of the IMP in one variable, then demonstrate how extending our methods to arbitrarily finite variables naturally leads to the construction of Gröbner bases. Following this, we will introduce CSPs, show how the IMP can be used to solve the graph coloring problem, then construct a general framework for translating CSPs into IMPs, following which we will compute Gröbner bases to determine ideal membership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling in Embedding Spaces</title>
      <link>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/topic_modeling_embedding_spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MikeLilley.github.io/posts/topic_modeling_embedding_spaces/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will be going over the paper Topic Modeling in Embedding Spaces by Dieng et al., with an extended explanation of the background content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://MikeLilley.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MikeLilley.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Experience Kansas State University Position: Research Assistant Location: Manhattan, KS, USA
Dates of Employment: August 2023 - Present Experience:
I am contributing to the development of an ontology graph for natural water resources in partnership with the Kansas Water Institute and SAS Institute, Inc. USS Vision, Inc. Position: Lead Machine Vision Engineer (1)
Machine Vision Engineer (2)
Location: Livonia, MI, USA
Dates of Employment: February 2024 - July 2024 (1) September 2021 - February 2024 (2) Experience:</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
